准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
拖延
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
滑浪学校
好了  同学们
Okay, class
安静  安静
quiet, quiet
请大家拿出纸笔
Now, get out your pencils and paper
记下作业
and write down the assignment
你听见了没
Did you hear that?
我们有作业
We get an assignment
所有人必须写一篇作文
Everyone must write an essay
主题是红绿灯前不能做的事
on what not to do at a stoplight
红绿灯
你听见了没
Did you hear that?
红绿灯前不能做的事
What not to do at a stoplight
不少于八百字
In no less than 800 words
你听见了没
Did you hear that?
八百字
800 words?
对  我知道
Yeah, I know
明天上交
Due tomorrow
同学们记住
And remember, class
认真做  不能偷懒
work hard and no goofing off
好  小蜗
Okay, Gary
不能偷懒
no goofing off
我要写出史上最佳的作文
I am about to write the greatest essay of all time
跟诸多佳作一样  这篇作文得写在
Like most great essays it will be written
纸上
on paper
比纸更重要的东西就是
Even more important than the paper is
铅笔
the pencil
铅笔可尖可钝
A pencil is sharp or as dull as I like
真奇怪
Funny
我点子一多起来  你就缩小了
as my ideas grow, you shrink
今天写作文最美好不过了
Well, I couldn't have asked for
a more beautiful day to write an essay
好  开始写了
Okay, here we go
红绿灯前不能做的事
"What Not To Do At A Stoplight"
还挺简单
This is easy
海绵宝宝作
"By SpongeBob Squarepants"
这作文精华满满
This essay is pure gold
现在呢  铅笔
And now, pencil
准备好开始动手吧
get ready to do your stuff
因为要开始写了
because here we go
红绿灯前不能做的事
海绵宝宝作
比我想得还要难
this is harder than I thought
快来啊  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
应该要立法禁止
It should be against the law
在这种阳光明媚的日子被迫写作文
to have to write an essay
on such a super sailorific, sunshiny day
但我必须做下去
But I must press onward
因为只要有这支铅笔
because with this pencil
再把作文写完
and the completion of this essay
我就能离我驾照更近一步了
I'll be one step closer to my driver's license
好耶
Oh, yeah
这应该不成问题
This'll be no problemo
我时间还不少呢
Why, I got plenty of time
现在才六点
It's only 6:00
好
Okay
好  开始写了
okay, here we go
开始写了
Here we go
有了  我只要
I know, I just need to
把体内的血液泵到脑袋里就行
get a little blood pumpin' in the old noodle
做点健美操怎么样
How about some calisthenics?
感受到血脉在偾张了
I can feel those juices pumpin' now
我在干什么
What am I doing?
必须得写作文
I got to write that paper
快啊  铅笔
Come on, pencil
写字啊
make words
小蜗
Gary
小蜗  我最爱的蜗牛近来可好
Gary, how's my favorite mollusk?
要不要让海绵宝宝
How about you let ol' SpongeBob
给你来点吃的
fix you up something to eat?
你说你不饿是什么意思
What do you mean, you're not hungry?
我知道我还得写作文
I know I have an essay to write
走吧  小蜗
Now come on, Gary
小蜗
蜗牛粮
我得确保你补充到营养了
I got to make sure you get your nutrition
所以你不吃光  我就不走
so I'm not leaving until you eat every single bite
小蜗  你确定你不想要
Gary, a-are you sure you don't want
来点焦糖布丁吗
some crème brulée?
也不想要巧克力味海草块吗
Or-or some chocoflavored algae bits?
小蜗搞得好乱
Gary sure made a mess
我可写不了作文
I can't work on my essay
全都得怪厨房乱糟糟的
knowing there's a mess in the kitchen
顺便把地板其他地方也打扫一下
I might as well clean the rest of the floor while I'm at it
卫生死角也得打扫
I should get these hard-to-reach places, too
盘子得洗干净
And these dishes need to be cleaned
肮脏垃圾可不能有
Can't have dirty garbage
现在应该够干净了
Well, I think it's clean enough now
也没花多长时间
Why, that didn't take too long
现在才
It's only
十点钟
10:00
不能再乱混了
No more fooling around
必须继续用功
I got to get back to work
好  作文先生
Okay, Mr. Essay
我说
I say
准备好让我写你吧
prepare to be written
我在写了
I'm doing it
好  好
Yeah, yeah
好
Yeah
再一点这个
And some of these
and some of these
就快好了  然后
Almost there and
完成
done
来看看目前为止写得怎么样了
Now let's see how it looks so far
夫
"The"
[ 无实义 ]
休息时间
Break time
走来走去有助于思考
Pacing always helps me think
我想想  只剩799个字了
Let's see, only 799 words to go
海绵宝宝  快点想啊
Think, SpongeBob, think
是  是谁
W-Who's that?
什么
Wha?
喂
Hello?
派大星  你在干什么
Hey, Patrick, what you up to?
睡觉
Sleeping
真是太迷人了
That's really fascinating
你睡得好吗
Are you having a good sleep?
要不交流一下你做了什么梦
Any dreams you'd like to discuss?
我还记得
I remember on the
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你我都知道你只是在利用我
You and I both know that you're just using me
让自己分心
as a distraction
这样你就暂时用不着写作文了
so you don't have to write your essay
这话不对
That is not true
我打电话是想跟你谈个引人入胜的话
I called to have an engaging conversation with you
你说我听
Well, I'm listening
马可
Marco
波罗
Polo
好
Yeah
那我就挂了  派大星
well I got to get going, Patrick
我有篇特重要的作文得写
Got an important essay to write
也太爱聊了
What a chatterbox
他难道听不出来我很忙吗
Can't he see that I'm busy?
纸上一堆橡皮屑  这样可写不了作文
I can't write with all these eraser shavings
all over my paper
橡皮屑飘得我思维空间到处都是
Now they're floating around my thinking space
再见了  讨厌的小屑屑
So long, pesky particles
我吞了一粒
I swallowed one
呛到我了
I'm choking
水
Water
刚才真是好险
That was a close one
你说大惊小怪是什么意思  小蜗
What do you mean overly dramatic, Gary?
刚才呛的那口让我肚子饿了
All that choking sure made me hungry
可不能饿着肚子就写作文  小蜗
I can't write on an empty stomach, Gary
得补充一点精神食粮
I got to have my brain food
来看看
Now, let's see
要白面包还是黑面包
white or rye bread?
还是黑麦粗面包
Or pumpernickel?
应该得看里面夹的是什么肉
I guess it really depends on the meat inside
还有奶酪
and the cheese
有人来了
A visitor?
找我的
For me?
邮件
你好
Hello
寄给海绵宝宝先生的包裹
Package for Mr. Squarepants
太棒了
Great
谢谢
Thanks
所以说
So, uh
你喜欢送信吗
you like delivering mail?
这是我的饭碗
It puts bread on the table
碗里是白面包还是黑麦粗面包
Rye or pumpernickel?
真是的
Oh, brother
所以说你自己的信是自己送的
So, do you deliver your own mail
还是说你有自己的邮递员会给你送
or do you have your own mailperson?
可是谁来送他的信
But then who delivers his mail?
是不是有没完没了一长串的邮递员
Is there a never-ending chain of mailmen
互相在给其他邮递员送信
delivering mail to other mailmen?
我估计邮筒理论上能断掉这串关系
Well, I guess a P.O. box
could, in theory break the chain
你不是还得写作文吗
Don't you have a paper to write?
他怎么知道我应该得写作文
How did he know I'm supposed to be writing an essay?
其他消息
In other news
突发新闻
本地居民海绵宝宝
local resident SpongeBob Squarepants
完成作文的时间仅剩数小时
only has a few hours left to complete his essay
并且他仍在偷懒
and yet he continues to goof off
他何时才会做功课
When will he learn?
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
看这边
Over here
过来  坐下吧
Come on, take a seat
把脚放上来  放松一下
Put your feet up and relax
完蛋
Oh, no
半夜了
Midnight
一定要
Must
回
get
到书桌前
back to desk
刚才真是好险
That was a close call
我的裤子
My pants
在下面
Down here
你给我上来
You get up here
我还得写作文
I got to get back to work
自由了
Freedom
裤子别跑
Stop, pants
你马上给我回来
You get back here this instant
裤子
pants
时间到了  海绵宝宝
Time's up, SpongeBob
要烧了
Burning
只剩799个字了
Only 799 words to go
不要
No
我都干了什么好事
What have I done?
救命
Help
救命  我家着火了
Help, my house is on fire
海绵宝宝  为什么
SpongeBob, why?
你为什么要放火烧我  海绵宝宝
Why did you set me on fire, SpongeBob?
为什么不写作文
Why didn't you just write your essay?
别浪费时间了
Stop wasting time
我作文在哪
Where's my essay?
你在这啊
There you are
我一定是睡着了
I must have dozed off
来看看  写到哪了
Let's see, where are we?
夫
敢不敢看看几点了
Do I dare look at the clock?
就快九点了
It's almost 9:00
五分钟后就要上课了
Class starts in five minutes
我五分钟怎么写得完一整篇作文
How am I going to write this whole paper in five minutes?
我怎么知道红绿灯前不能做什么
How am I supposed to know what not to do at a stoplight?
红绿灯前不能喂蜗牛
Feeding your snail
is something not to do at a stoplight
也不能做三明治  也不能点蜡烛
and making a sandwich and-and lighting candles
也不能喝水  也不能打电话找朋友
and drinking water and calling your friends
也不能劈电视
and karate chopping the TV
也不能跟邮递员闲聊
and shooting the breeze with the mailman
也不能睡着  也不能
and falling asleep and
滑浪学校
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff
泡芙老师  我写完了
Mrs. Puff, I'm finished
八百字全写完了
All 800 words
写完了
I'm finished
我要交给你
Here it is
都
They
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff?
大家都去哪了
Where is everybody?
你在这啊  海绵宝宝
There you are, SpongeBob
我要交给你  泡芙老师
Here you go, Mrs. Puff
八百字
800 words
主题是红绿灯及红绿灯前不能做的事
all about stoplights and what not to do at them
对不起  海绵宝宝
I'm sorry, SpongeBob
我之前给你打过电话
I tried to call you
我得去参加教研会
I have to go to a teachers' convention
可我作文怎么办
But what about my essay?
我决定要取消作业
I decided to cancel the assignment
改去红绿灯前实地考察
We're just going to
take a field trip to a stoplight instead
下周再见
See you next week
我和傻瓜
在一起
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
扫  扫
Sweep, sweep
需要
Need
家具
furniture
派大星  你干嘛在做装修
Patrick, what's with the home improvement?
派大星
Hey, Patrick
扫  扫
Sweep, sweep
派大星  我过来是要问你
Well, Patrick, I came over to see
想不想去捉水母
if you wanted to go jellyfishing
不过看得出来你一直在忙自己的
but I can see you're busy having an episode
知道吗  海绵宝宝
You know something, Spongebob?
你就只想着玩
it's just all fun and games for you
什么都跟你没关系
Nothing really matters
我们去捉水母吧
"Let's go jelly fishing
我们什么都不用做
"We don't have any work to do
生活就像一大碗精制什锦腰果
"Life is just a big bowl of fancy, assorted cashews
大家都用不着掸灰  用不着清理
"and nobody has anything to dust or to clean
用不着擦干净  用不着瞎编
or to wipe, or fabricate"
可是派大星
But, Patrick
我只见过你清理盘子
the only thing I've ever seen you clean is your plate
我不知道该怎么办  海绵宝宝
I don't know what to do, Spongebob
一定要帮帮我
You got to help me
派大星  你又忘了怎么吃东西了
Patrick, you forgot how to eat again
走吧  拿漏斗来
Come on, we'll get the funnel
不是那回事  海绵宝宝
No, it's not that, Spongebob
有更严重的
it's worse
我还挺喜欢漏斗的
Darn, I like the funnel
什么事那么严重
Well, what is it then?
你看
Look
一张字条
A note
音 符
对  可你再看背面
Yeah, but turn it over
有封信
There's a letter
字母
确实
You're right
而且我还收到了我爸妈的消息
And I got this message from my parents
你爸妈
Your parents?
亲爱的派大星  我和你妈
"Dear Patrick, Your mom and I
明天要来过海星节了
"are coming out tomorrow for Starfish Day
尽量想起来  不过别想太用力了
"Please try to remember, but don't try too hard
不然又会像上次那样受伤
"or you'll hurt yourself like last time
爱你的  爸爸
Love, Daddy"
海绵宝宝  我爸妈觉得
Spongebob, my parents think
我比一大袋尿布还要笨
I'm dumber than a sack of diapers
才不是这样  派大星
No, they don't, Patrick
爸妈就喜欢玩激将法
Parents just like to push your buttons
按 钮
像这样
like this--
那么玩总能让我振作起来
That always cheers me up
可今天不一样
But not today
派大星  要是你爸妈觉得你很笨
Patrick, if your parents think you're dumb
那他们肯定不知道真笨是什么样的
then they must not know what dumb really is
可他们不看电视的吗
But don't they watch television?
那就是我意思  派大星
That's what I'm saying, Pat
如果你爸妈见到了个真笨蛋
If your parents got to meet a real dummy
那他们就会发现你有多天才了
they'd realize what genius you really are
可灯神不是住灯里的吗
But don't genius live in a lamp?
天 才
并且我们也不认识笨蛋
And besides, we don't know any dumb people
放心  派大星
Don't worry, Patrick
我来当笨蛋
I'll be the dummy
等到你爸妈看到我表现有多笨
When your parents see how dumb I act
他们就会当你是史上最聪明的人了
they'll think you're the smartest guy ever
数学力量大
Math is power
ABCD
A, B, C, D
EFG
E, F, G
HIJKLMNO
H, I, J, K, L, M, N, O
是不是得再拿喇叭出来  马蒂
Should I get the bullhorn again, Marty?
WXYZ
W, X, Y and Z?
妈妈好
Hi, Mom
爸爸好
Hi, Dad
儿子  你这次认得我们了
Son, you recognized us this time
我怎么就不认得我自己的亲生父母了
Why wouldn't I recognize my own parents?
你脑子一直不是很灵光
You never were a bright one
不来带我们参观一下你家吗
Well, aren't you going to show us inside?
他可能都忘了家在哪了
He probably forgot where it is
我知道在哪
I know where
我来带路  这样才不会迷路
Let me lead the way so we don't get lost, huh?
手牵手
Hold hands now
好  就快要到了
Okay, we're almost there
数到三放手
Let go on three
一
One
二
two
三
three
好样的
Good job
拍拍派大星
Pats for Patrick
我去拿饮料来
I'll go get the beverages
儿子
Son
你这回把饮料拿东西装起来了
You put the drinks in something this time
儿子  你一定整晚都在努力
Son, you must've been working all night
为我们好好打理
to put these together for us
我们爱你
We love you
万岁  白痴来了
Hooray, the idiot's here
我是说  我来开门
I mean, I'll get it
防护头盔
Protective helmet--
戴好了
check
我就该这么扮傻的  小蜗
I'm supposed to look stupid, Gary
怎么可能会出差错呢
What could go wrong?
太惊喜了
What a surprise
嗨
Hi
爸  妈
Mom, Dad
认识下我邻居  海绵宝宝
meet my neighbor, Spongebob
嗨
Hi
你好啊
Hello there
真是幸会
How do you do?
嗨
Hi
握个手
Put her there
放 上 来
妈妈  妈妈
Mama, Mama
他说的是握手
He means shake
摇 晃
不对  海绵宝宝
No, Spongebob, no
握的是手
Shake hands
摇
不对  海绵宝宝
No, Spongebob
抓住我爸的手
Grab my dad's hand
只用一只手抓住
Grab it with only one hand
真乖
Good boy
再上下动你的胳膊
Now move your arm up and down
所以说  海绵宝宝
So, Spongebob
你住在附近吗
do you live nearby?
嗨
Hi
不对  海绵宝宝
No, Spongebob
给他们看看你家
Show them your house
不是女式衬衫
No, not your blouse
[ blouse（女式衬衫）与 house（房子）谐音 ]
是你家
your house
他住水果里的
He lives in a fruit?
太不健康了
That's unhealthy
海绵宝宝
Hey, Spongebob
要来共进晚餐吗
You want to stay for dinner?
他吃完东西都会那样吗
Does he always do that after he eats?
就星期三那样
Only on Wednesday
派大星  你朋友可能脑子坏了
Patrick, I think your friend might be broken
没错  而且得用不少遮蔽胶带
Yeah, and it would take more than some masking tape
才可以修好他
to fix that guy
他不会有事吧
Is he going to be okay?
没关系的
That's nothing
你们应该看他每天早上
You should see him in the morning
边跳边喊
prancing around, yelling
我准备好了
I'm ready
把邻居全逼疯了
He drives all the neighbors crazy
先前有一天
Why, just the other day
我们邻居章鱼哥
our neighbor Squidward was
他根本没救了
There's really no help for him
你们看他的衣着
I mean, look at the way he's dressed
只有脑袋钻了洞的
Only somebody with holes drilled in their head
才会这么穿
would wear that stuff
还有这形状怎么说
And how about this shape?
我听说过胸肌发达
I mean, I've heard of barrel-chested
可没听说过胸肌发方
but never box-chested
海绵宝宝
Hey, Spongebob
我能不能找你借睫毛膏
do you have any mascara I could borrow?
那男孩子还化妆
The boy wears makeup?
太好笑了
What a card
派大星
Hey, Patrick
Patrick
他喊了我名字
He said my name
你怎么把他训到那种程度的
How'd you train him to do that?
他咬我
He bit me
派大星  来厨房找我
Patrick, meet me in the kitchen
笨蛋大概是想找我私下聊聊了
I guess the dummy wants to have a private conversation
聊的是笨话
A dumb one
请问有什么问题
So, what's on your mind?
不对  等下
No, wait
我已经知道你什么问题了
I already know the answer
没头脑
nothing
看吧  可好笑了
See, that's funny
因为你就是笨死了
'cause you're dumb
派大星  能不能尽量少侮辱我一点
Patrick, could you
let up on the insults just a little bit?
刚刚那些给你整不会了吗
We're those too complicated for you?
我尽量试试傻瓜化一点
I'll try dumbing them down a bit
派大星  我感觉你真觉得我笨了
Patrick, I get the feeling that
you think I really am dumb
我和笨蛋在一起
我就等你这么说
That's just what I'd expect you to say
笨蛋就是完全不会发现
Dumb people are always blissfully unaware
自己有多笨
of how dumb they really are
我这只是在装笨
I'm only pretending to be dumb
这可是我们计划  记得吗
It was our plan, remember?
海绵宝宝  要是你能看出来
Oh, Spongebob, if only you could see
你说的话有多笨就好了
how stupid you sound right now
还非得高谈阔论幻想出来的计划
with your talk of imaginary plans
跟你说吧  你让我心情特别好
Tell you what, you've caught me in a good mood
就顺从你一下吧
I'll humor you
去吧
Go on
快出去给大家表现聪明点
Go out there and act smart for everyone
好  可以
Okay, I will
你放心好了
And-and don't worry
我会帮你捂热的
I'll keep this warm for you
我摊牌了
I have a confession to make
刚刚做的傻事都是骗你们的
I lied about being stupid
我只是在装傻
I just acted like a fool
这样你们才能再稍微多重视派大星
so you would appreciate Patrick a little bit more
我会说话  会吃饭
I know how to talk and eat
还会洗衣服
and do laundry--
我还分得清黑白
I even separate the darks and the lights
那我们就从头来过吧
So what do you say we start over and try again
嗨
Hi
我叫海绵宝宝
My name is Spongebob Squarepants
而且我不笨
and I am not a dummy
太神了
Amazing
在厨房待上个三分钟
Three minutes in the kitchen
我们儿子就教会他
and our son has taught him
用完整的句子说话了
to talk in complete sentences
好样的  儿子
Good work, son
这趟不容易  爸
It wasn't easy, Dad
可可可
B-but-but
看来你现在又得上说话课了  年轻人
It looks like it's time for your next lesson, young man
都听好了
Now listen to me
我不笨
I'm not dumb
我有大脑
I have a brain
看  这是照片
See, here's a picture of it
想必本来就那么大吧
That must be actual size
不对
No
我大脑大小正常  功能也正常
It's normal size and fully functional
看好了
Watch
二加二等于四
Two plus two equals four
儿子  你还教了他数学
Oh, son, you taught him math, too
不对
No
你还教了他唱歌
And you taught him to sing
现在他短路了
Now he's short-circuiting
一定是你把他教过头了
You must've taught him a little too much
儿子  你要知道
You know, son
我心里一直清楚你的智力
I've always known that when it comes to brightness
也就跟三瓦灯泡的亮度差不多
well, you're about a three-watt
但是这位
But this guy
他就是漆黑洞穴里点不着的湿火柴
he's a wet match in a dark cave
显得接线员都比他聪明
He makes phone operators seem smart
儿子  不过更重要的是
But more importantly, son
他让我明白了你现在变得有多聪明
he's shown me
what a sharp, quick-witted boy you've become
感觉现在我才算是真正认识了你
I-I feel like I'm really meeting you for the first time
你说对吧  珍妮特
Isn't that right, Janet?
那当然了  马蒂
You bet, Marty
珍妮特
Janet?
马蒂
Marty?
你们都是谁啊
Who are you people?
马蒂  我好怕
Marty, I'm scared
不好意思
Excuse me
这可爱的夫妇俩是你家的吗
Does this lovely couple belong to you?
他们站在我家外面喊
They've been standing outside my house saying
派大星在哪  已经一整天了
"Where's Patrick?" all day
快让我烦死了
It's driving me nuts
妈
Mom
爸
Dad
儿子  你这次认得我们了
Son, you actually recognized us this time
而且你今天还记得穿衣服
And you remembered to get dressed today
对了  亲爱的
That's right, honey
我们没生儿子
we don't have a son
还真是
Oh, yeah